

Arturo Rodríguez Olvera

Software Engineer

5541331992 Tlalnepantla Edo. De México arturorodr96@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/arturordz



Profile.

Software engineer with 5+ years of experience in the development life cycle and experience in software and hardware integration. I have the strong conviction to always keep learning new technologies and apply them to grow personally and professionally.



Education.

Instituto Politécnico Nacional (2014 – 2019)

Escuela Superior de Ingeniería Mecánica y Eléctrica. **Electronics and Communications Engineering** Major: Computer Science



Languages.

ReactJS

AWS EC2 | ECR | ECS



English Spanish



Skills.

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- NodeJS
- NestJS
- **Express**

- Jest
- GIT
- CosmosDB
- MongoDB
- **PostgreSQL**



Work Experience.

Luxoft (September 2022 – Currently)

Intermountain Health Care Senior Backend Developer

Job Description:

- Align with Architect and PO on technical solutions sizing and backlog grooming.
- Collaborate with Frontend tasks using reactis.
- Design and develop rest API's for web and mobile applications using node.js along nestjs framework.
- Debug, fix, and improve the quality of our current code and write unit tests using jest.

Honeywell (May 2022 – September 2022)

HCE Project

Senior Backend Developer

Job Description:

- Design and Develop rest API's for authentication and authorization using nest is and PostgreSQL as database system.
- Debug and fix.
- Write unit tests using jest.

Globant (April 2021 - April 2022)

Greatminds Project

Backend Developer

Job Description:

- Design and develop rest API's for an education web platform using node is along nest and postgreSQL
- Develop and debug lambda functions using nestjs framework.
- Write unit tests using jest.
- Create queries in order to find data issues in the database.
- Debug, fix, and improve the quality of our current code.



Walmart (August 2020 - April 2021)

Ecommerce Technology Backend Developer

Job Description:

- Design and develop a middle layer to integrate internal services with different ecommerce frontends (Bodega, Sam's, Superama, etc) based on the design pattern backend for frontend using node.js and mongoDB as database system.
- Write unit tests using jest.

GoNet (January 2020 - August 2020)

Rappi pay project

Backend Developer

Job Description:

- Design and develop microservices using java springboot and node.js to integrate rappi core with bank services for credit and debit card of rappi using postgreSQL as database system.
- Debug and fix the current code.

PowerStreet (April 2018 - November 2019)

Development Area

Web Developer Jr

Job Description:

- · Develop backend services and frontend clients to show information about an ERP software
- Migration of a monolitic web platform to microservices
- Design and develop API's to integrate with external information systems using MEVN as our main tech stack
- Design and develop a system using web sockets for tracking and choose the best delivery route for distributors